chicagobears.com 2014-03-28

# Chicago Bears | Privacy policy

## Chicago Bears Website Privacy Policy

**_Last updated on February 23, 2013._ **

This privacy policy applies to the Chicago Bears website located at www.ChicagoBears.com the Chicago Bears' various social networking profiles, and communications from the Chicago Bears (collectively, the "Website"). The purpose of this privacy policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.

The Chicago Bears Football Club has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers information collected through [www.chicagobears.com](http://www.chicagobears.com/) but not our social networking profiles. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint) .

The Chicago Bears Football Club complies with the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the from European Union member countries. The Chicago Bears Football Club has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view The Chicago Bears Football Club's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/> .

Please read the information below to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.

1\. Information We Collect on the Website   
2\. How We Use The Information Collected   
3\. Sharing of Your Information  
4\. Chat Rooms, Forums, And Message Boards   
5\. Links To Other Websites   
6\. Security   
7\. A Special Note For Parents Concerning Privacy   
8\. Notification Of Changes And Your Acceptance Of The Privacy Policy   
9\. Correcting/Updating Personal Information   
10\. Your California Privacy Rights   
11\. Questions About This Privacy Policy 

**1\. Information We Collect On The Website:** "Personal Identifiable Information" or "Personal Information" is information that can be used to identify you as an individual or allow someone to contact you. When other information, such as a favorite team or player, is associated with personal information, it also becomes Personal Information for purposes of this Policy. We collect Personal Information such as your full name, telephone number, street address, email address, unique identifiers (like your Message Board User ID and password), demographic information (like your date of birth, age, gender, ticket holder status, game attendance, marital status, or number of children), and financial information (like your credit or debit card number) in various ways and for various reasons.

Web site operators cannot condition participation in an activity on the user providing more personal information than is reasonably necessary for the activity. Users can review their personal information, have it deleted and refuse to permit any further collection by visiting the My Chicago Bears Preference Center or by contacting the Chicago Bears at [fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com) .

**Email Communications:** When you open emails from us, we may receive a confirmation noting you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of what emails we send you and what emails you may be receiving from our subsidiaries and affiliates. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have opted to receive or not to receive.

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:

**Registration:**

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:

**Registration:** You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer, such as newsletters or contests. Participation in registration is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

**Newsletters and Website Emails:** We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Website, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Website. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. You may also cancel your free email subscription by emailing [fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com) or by following the instructions provided on the Website or in the newsletter or email.

**Send To A Friend:** If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friends email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. The Chicago Bears do not store this information after sending this one-time email.

**Contests or Sweepstakes:** We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes, (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used).

We may also ask your permission to allow us to publicly post some of your information on the Website, such as on a winner's page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Website, and collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we do not collect your information and we have no control over the information collected from you. Accordingly, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.

**Surveys or Voting:** From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

**Games:** When you register to play games or trivia on our Website, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information.

**Cookies:** As with many Websites, our Website uses a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a unique, random number that is stored in the browser on your computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify you, just the computer that is used to visit the site.

Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit the Website. Cookies also let us know how many people visit our website and where visitors go on the site. In addition, cookies can let us know non-personally identifiable information, like what web browser is being used to access the website. For registered users, cookies can make using the Website easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Website, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Website are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Website. Cookies may also allow the Website to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Website, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. Cookies, log files and web-beacons are not tied to a user's personally identifiable information.

Some of our business partners, sponsors or advertisers, use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by www.ChicagoBears.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.

**Web Beacons and Other Tracking Technology:** Our Website uses a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including Web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of Web sites. We also use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on our Web sites, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of our Web sites. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML e-mails that we send our guests to determine whether our guests have opened those e-mails and/or clicked on links in those e-mails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable.

**IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data:** We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the internet, like your ISP (Internet Service Provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information. Click-stream data is information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.

**Transaction Information:** If you conduct a financial transaction with our Website, such as order information from our Website, buy our merchandise, or subscribe to services offered on our Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and financial information. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the information, products or other services that you order, and to invoice you. For your protection, such information is collected and stored through encrypted means.

**2\. HOW WE USE INFORMATION COLLECTED**

As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used to:

>   * contact you about the Website;
>   * contact you relating your membership status and/or subscriptions;
>   * respond to your requests, questions and concerns;
>   * confirm or fulfill an order you have made;
>   * inform you of a prize you have won and deliver it to you;
>   * monitor or improve the use of the Website;
>   * customize the advertising and content you see;
>   * monitor compliance with our terms and conditions of use of the Website;
>   * assess the level of interest in, and use of, the Website, our e-mails and our other messaging campaigns both on an individual basis and in the aggregate; and
>   * send you our promotional material and special offers and those of third parties.
> 

**3\. SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION  
**

At times, we may share your personal information with others for various purposes. The following outlines the ways in which your information may be shared with others and the ways in which you may opt-out of having your information shared:

**Agents:** We employ other businesses, certain services and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Website analysis, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They may have access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for their own purposes, like sending you marketing offers about their products.

These sites include:   
* Club Seat Season Ticket Holders My Club Connection ( [https://oss.ticketmaster.com/html/home.htmI?team=bears&l=EN&STAGE=1](https://oss.ticketmaster.com/html/home.htmI?team=bears&l=EN&STAGE=1)   
* Chicago Bears Store ( <http://store.chicagobears.com/> )

**Aggregate Information:** We may share aggregate information, such as demographics and Website usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors or other organizations. When this type of information is shared, the other parties do not have access to your personally identifiable information.

**Other Promotional Offers:** We may send offers to you on behalf of our marketing partners. When we do this, we do not give that partner your name and address. If you do not want to receive such offers, you may use the opt out method detailed in the email or change your preferences by selecting the update preferences link.

**Administrative or Legal Process:** Your personal information may be transferred to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, law enforcement agencies, to protect our rights, or protect the rights of other users of this website.

**4\. CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS, AND MESSAGE BOARDS**

The Website may make chat rooms, forums and message boards available to its users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. When a user signs up on the message boards they are doing so on a 3rd party service providers web site even though it has the look and feel of the Chicago Bears site. The Chicago Bears privacy statement governs the information collection and use submitted on the message boards. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas.

**5\. LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

You should be aware that when you are on the Website you could be directed to other Websites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Website onto a different Website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and marketing partners that may use the Website's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other Websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a Website that is linked to our Website, you should consult that Website's privacy policy before providing any personal information.

**6\. SECURITY**

This Website incorporates reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information that we may collect and we have put into place reasonable precautions to protect such information from loss, misuse and alteration. Your personally identifiable information is transferred to our computers utilizing encryption software. Only those employers who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised as required.

If we believe that the security of your Personal Information in our care may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. If a notification is appropriate, we will endeavor to notify you as promptly as possible under the circumstances. If we have your e-mail address, we may notify you by e-mail. **You consent to our use of e-mail as a means of such notification. If you prefer for us to use the U.S. Postal Service to notify you in this situation, please e-mail us at[fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com).**

**7\. A SPECIAL NOTE TO PARENTS CONCERNING PRIVACY**

The Website is a general audience Website. We do not collect any personal information from or about children under the age of thirteen on the Website, except through our Kids Club registration process. If you register your child for the Kids Club, you consent to the Chicago Bears Football Club’s collection and storage of the information you provide. You are asked to provide your child’s personal information, including your child’s full name, mailing address and date of birth. This information will only be used to distribute information about, and related to, the Kids Club. We will not ask for any personal information about your child, beyond what is reasonably necessary for your child to participate in the Kids Club. We do not share personally identifiable information with any third parties for commercial purposes, and the information that you provide to us will not be rented or sold to any third party under any circumstances. You may review the information collected about your child, and remove your child from the Kids Club at any time by contacting our Fan Services department at [fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com).

**8\. YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES TO THE POLICY**

By using this Website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on our website and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address. We will assume that you have given your permission for your information to be used under the terms of the new privacy policy, if you do not respond to our email within thirty days or continue to use the Website thirty days after a notice is posted. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.

**9\. CORRECTING/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION**

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your email address or zip code), or if you no longer desire to access our Website, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update, delete or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by using an opt out message in an email, or by emailing us at [fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com) . We will respond to your request within 10-20 business days.

Users can update their information with regards to the Bears Direct email newsletter by clicking on the "update preferences" link at the bottom of Bears Direct emails. Users wishing to update their Chicago Bears Store account can do so by accessing the "My Account" section within the store.

**Data Retention:** We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at fanservices@chicagobears.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**10\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

A California privacy law that went into effect on January 1, 2005, allows California residents to obtain specific information about a business's privacy practices if it shares information with other companies for those companies' direct marketing purposes.

As explained in this privacy policy, whenever you agree to let us collect personal information about you, we will always provide you with an option to prevent this information from being shared for non-administrative purposes with third parties. You can exercise this option at any time by following the steps outlined above.

Because this website has a comprehensive privacy policy and provides you with details on how you may opt-in / opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes, we are not required to provide you with this information.

CA Privacy Rights   
Chicago Bears   
1920 Football Drive   
Lake Forest, IL 60045

**11\. QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the privacy practices of this Website, contact [fanservices@chicagobears.com](mailto:fanservices@chicagobears.com)

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to:[](http://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/National-Football-League/validation?rid=65b265da-900d-4199-9b01-3f89a89a6307)

Chicago Bears Football Club  
Attn: New Media Department  
Website Privacy Policy  
1920 Football Drive  
Lake Forest, IL 60045
